How to Train Your Dragon 2 is a fantasy, action,
adventure film directed by Dean DeBlois.
Five years have passed since Hiccup and Toothless
united the dragons and Vikings of Berk.
Now, they spend their time charting unmapped territories.
During one of their adventures, the pair discover a secret cave that houses
hundreds of wild dragons -- and a mysterious dragon rider.
Now, Hiccup and Toothless find themselves at the center of a
battle to protect Berk from a power-hungry warrior.
Hiccup (voice), played by Jay Baruchel.
Valka (voice), played by Cate Blanchett.
Stoick (voice), played by Gerard Butler.
Gobber (voice), played by Craig Ferguson.
Astrid (voice), played by America Ferrera.
Snotlout (voice), played by Jonah Hill.
How to Train Your Dragon 2 is a 2014 American animated fantasy film written and
directed by Dean DeBlois, based on the book series by Cressida Cowell.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation, it is the second
installment in the How to Train Your Dragon trilogy.
Jay Baruchel, America Ferrera, Gerard Butler, Craig Ferguson, Jonah
Hill, Christopher Mintz-Plasse, Kristen Wiig and T.J.
Miller reprise their roles from the first film, with Cate Blanchett,
Djimon Hounsou, and Kit Harington joining the cast.
Set five years after the events of the first film, it follows 20-year-old Hiccup and his friends as they encounter Valka,
Hiccup's long-lost mother, and Drago Bludvist, a madman who wants to conquer the world by use of a dragon army.
A sequel to How to Train Your Dragon was announced in April
2010, with the outline first drafted in February.
DeBlois, who co-directed the first film, agreed to return on the
condition he would be allowed to make a trilogy.
He cited The Empire Strikes Back (1980) and My Neighbor Totoro (1988) as his main
inspirations, with the expanded scope of the former being particularly influential.
DeBlois and his creative team visited Svalbard to
look for inspirations for the setting.
Composer John Powell returned to score the film.
It was DreamWorks' first film to use scalable multi-core processing
and the studio's new animation and lighting software.
How to Train Your Dragon 2 premiered at the 2014 Cannes Film Festival on May 16, 2014,
and was released in the United States on June 13 by 20th Century Fox.
Like its predecessor, it received critical acclaim, with
praise for its animation and emotional depth.
It grossed $622 million, becoming the 12th-highest-grossing film of 2014.
The film won the Golden Globe for Best Animated Feature and six Annie Awards, including Best
Animated Feature, and was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Animated Feature.
The final installment in the trilogy, How to Train Your
Dragon: The Hidden World, was released in 2019.
A live-action remake is scheduled for release in 2027.
The film explores themes of rescue, husband wife relationship,
sacrifice, parent child relationship, loss of loved one.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking and intense.